duq.edu 2012-09-20

# Internet Privacy Policy | Duquesne University

A  A  Email  Print Share 

### Collecting and Using Personal Information

When you visit and navigate our sites and when you communicate with us via our sites, we will not collect personal information about you unless you provide us that information voluntarily. Any non-public personal information that you may provide via our sites will be used solely for the purpose stated on the page where it is collected. Duquesne University will not sell, license, transmit or disclose this information outside of Duquesne University unless (a) expressly authorized by you, (b) necessary to enable Duquesne University contractors or agents to perform certain functions for us, or (c) required or permitted by law. In all cases, we will disclose the information consistent with applicable laws and regulations and we will require the recipient to protect the information and use it only for the purpose it was provided.

By “personal information,” we mean data that is unique to an individual, such as a name, address, Social Security number, e-mail address, or telephone number. From time to time, we may request personal information from you at our sites in order to deliver requested materials to you or respond to your questions.

##### Your E-Mail

Please note that your e-mail, like most, if not all, non-encrypted Internet e-mail communications, may be accessed and viewed by other Internet users, without your knowledge and permission, while in transit to us. For that reason, to protect your privacy, please do not use e-mail to communicate information to us that you consider confidential. If you wish, you may contact us instead via non-cellular telephone at the numbers provided at various locations on our sites.

There are some locations on Duquesne University’s websites where we have made special provisions for a more secure environment in which we can exchange information with you. At each of these locations, we will provide you with appropriate instructions.

##### Other Information / Cookies

You should also be aware that when you visit our websites, we collect certain information that does not identify you personally, but provides us with “usage data,” such as the number of visitors we receive or what pages are visited most often. This data helps us to analyze and improve the usefulness of the information we provide at these websites.

Like most website owners, we may also use what is known as “cookie” technology. A “cookie” is an element of data that a website can send to your browser when you link to that website. It is not a computer program and has no ability to read data residing on your computer or instruct it to perform any step or function. By assigning a unique data element to each visitor, the website is able to recognize repeat users, track usage patterns and better serve you when you return to that site. The cookie does not extract other personal information about you, such as your name or address. Most browsers provide a simple procedure that will enable you to control whether you want to receive cookies by notifying you when a website is about to deposit a cookie file.

##### Linking to Other Sites

From time to time, Duquesne University websites may provide links to other websites, not owned or controlled by Duquesne University, that we think might be useful or of interest to you. We cannot, however, be responsible for the privacy practices used by other website owners or the content or accuracy of those other websites. Links to various non-Duquesne University websites do not constitute or imply endorsement by Duquesne University of these websites, any products or services described on these sites, or of any other material contained in them.

##### Security

Duquesne University has adopted and adheres to stringent security standards designed to protect non-public personal information at duq.edu against accidental or unauthorized access or disclosure. Among the safeguards that Duquesne University has developed for this site are administrative, physical and technical barriers that together form a protective firewall around the information stored at this site.

##### Changes to This Statement

Duquesne University may change this Statement from time to time; when updates are made, the Web Privacy Statement version date (located at the bottom of this page) will also be updated to reflect that a revision occurred. We encourage you to periodically reread this page to see if there have been any changes that may affect you. This Statement is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.

_Last updated: May 7, 2007_
